A Guide to the Donald R. Griffin papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA164
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1
  - O (Box 9, Folder 87)
    Oaks, Emily C. - Utah State University; sound recording equipment. O'Brien, John P. - Marquette University; bat suppliers. Odend'hal, Stewart - University of California-Davis;. Odum, Eugene P. - University of Georgia; Huyck Preserve. Odum, H. T. - Duke University; radar; Yale University. Ojasti, Juhani - Universidad Central de Caracas; Venezuelan bats and birds. O'Kelley, T.G. - rabbit supplier. Olive, Jeannie and Lindsay - University of North Carolina; duck heart rate. Oliver, James - bird's eye capabilities. Onion, Daniel K. - sound equipment; deer; New Hampshire; Maine; Harvard University. Organization for Tropical Studies - J. T. Spencer; Costa Rica; Fernando Nottebohm. Oring, Lewis - bird migration and calls; University of North Dakota; Michael Avery. Orr, Robert T. - California Academy of Sciences; bat sounds; equipment.
  - O'Mahony, Eugene (Box 9, Folder 88)
    James S. Fairley; Irish mammalogists; National Museum of Ireland; photos
  - Osgood, Frederick L., Jr. (Box 9, Folder 89)
    mammalogist; Vermont; caves; bat banding
  - P-Q (Box 9, Folder 90)
    Packard, Fred - bats, caves; Austin Ornithological Research Station; Harvard; National Park Service; Olympic National Park;. Painleve, Jean - Institut de Cinematographie Scientifique; film. Painter, Ben - Armstrong Junior College; Georgia; birds. Palmer, Ralph S. - seal meat; foxes; U.S. Naval Reserve; Vassar College. Park, Mrs. Francis E., Jr. (Catherine) - bat counting. Parker, John G. - Wisconsin; bats. Parkes, W. Raymond - Liverpool University Medical School. Payne, Charles L. - ultrasonic whistle. Payne, Fernandez - University of Indiana; echolocation; Walter Hahn. Pear, C. B., Jr. - Washington Institute of Technology; homing pigeons. Pendexter, Ursula - bats in house. Penney, Richard Lee - Iowa; Rockefeller University Institute for Research in Animal Behavior; penguins; Beebe Tropical Research Station; New York Zoological Society; U.S. Department of Agriculture. Pennington, Anthony J. - Princeton Engineer; article; Brush Recorder. Pennoyer, F. W., Jr. - bat sound reproduction; Naval Air Material Center. Pennsylvania, Commonwealth of - Department of Health; rabid bats; Ernest J. Witte. Pennycuick, Colin V. - Bristol University; wind tunnel; Ransome. Pepperberg, Irene Maxine - Purdue University; bird communication; H. F. Guggenheim Foundation. Perdeck, A. C. - radar equipment for tracking birds; Radio Research Instrument Co.; Netherlands. Perry, Tom L., Jr. - Harvard friend; caves; bats; Oxford. Peterson, Roger Tory - personal papers. Peto, H. R. - boat in Maine. Pettit, T. - Hunter Mountain property (Catskills); bird navigation. Phillips, W. W. A. - Tonacombe Group; Ceylon. Phipps and Bird Inc. - laboratory equipment supplier. Pielemeier, W. H. - Pennsylvania State College; bat sound measurement. Pierce, G. W. - Harvard University Physics Dept.; bat sounds and equipment; Fazil Khan. Pike, Oliver G. - echolocation; Nature article; England; photography. Pinchot, Gifford B., M.D. - airplane tracking; bird navigation. Pincus, G - Clark University; bat observations; Dr. Werthesen. Pitcairn, Lachlan and Mrs. Raymond - Tonshi Mountain property (Catskills); night bird migration sounds. Platt, C. S. - Agricultural Experiment station, New Jersey; Rutgers University; pigeons. Player, Jonathan - Guyana caves; England. Pobowski, Miss G. - bats. Poduschka, Walter - Austria; hedgehog sounds; equipment; Volkswagen Foundation. Pollak, George - Yale University; reference; bats. Pope, Alton S., M.D. - Dept. of Public Health, Massachusetts; bats, moles. Post, William - Caribbean Primate Research Station; Puerto Rico. Pratt, David - Harvard University; Woods Hole;. Pratt, John G. - Duke University; parapsychology; pigeon homing; Office of Naval Research; Ursula Von St. Paul;. Preble, Norman A. - University of Kansas; bat banding. Prescott, Hubert W. - Montana; shrews. Presti, David - University of Oregon; birds; geomagnetic fields. Pribram, Karl H. - Stanford University; Yerkes's Primate Research Center;. The Princeton Engineer - Anthony J. Pennington; bird sonar and military radar. Pronko, N. H. - University of Wichita; bird navigation. Pumphrey, R. J. - University of Liverpool; pulse in larynx. Quantico Post School - Marjorie Molyneaux; biology class request. Quine, Doug - Dalhousie University; Rockefeller University.
  - Palme, Arthur (Box 9, Folder 91)
    bat banding; Mount Greylock State Reservation Commission; Massachusetts
  - Papi, Floriano (Box 9, Folder 92)
    Universita di Pisa, Italy; ultrasonic equipment; bird navigation; smells in pigeon homing; Rhodes University
  - Parker, Henry M. (Box 9, Folder 93)
    WWII letters; Harvard friend; Germany; France; Signal Pigeon Company
  - Payne, Roger S. (Box 9, Folder 94)
    Cornell University; ornithology; Office of Naval Research; Museum of Natural History; Audubon Society Station; Rockefeller University; whales; Argentina
  - Pearson, O. Payne (Box 9, Folder 95)
    bird flight; Swarthmore College; University of California, Berkeley; Elizabeth Levine; Colombia
  - Perry, Clay (Box 9, Folder 96)
    caving; bat banding; Arthur Palme; Massachusetts; National Speleological Society
  - Phelps, William H., Jr. (Box 9, Folder 97)
    Venezuela birds and bats; de Bellard; Creole Oil
  - Publishers -Doubleday and Co. (Box 10, Folder 98)
    Educational Services Inc.; Physical Science Study Committee; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Bird Migration; Echoes of Bats and Men; Orientation of Bats; Natural History Press
  - Publishers - Dover Publications (Box 10, Folder 99)
    Listening in the Dark; Bird Migration; Doubleday; Yale University Press
  - Publishers - MacMillan and Co. (Box 10, Folder 100)
    Nature
  - Publishers - National Geographic (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Publishers - Other (Box 10, Folder 102)
    Academic Press; American Journal of Physics; American Scientist; Anima; Arete Publishing Company; ASP Biological and Medical Press; Bird-Banding; Birkhauser Boston, Inc.; Book of Knowledge; William C. Brown Co.; Bulletin of Museum of Comparative Zoology; Cambridge University Press; Richard Carrington; Cornell University Press; Ecology; Editions VDB; Encyclopedia Britannica; Euclides; W. H. Freeman and Company; Greenwood Press; Grolier Society; Harper's Magazine; Harrow House; Harvard University Press; D.C. Heath and Co.; Houghton Mifflin Co.; Hunter-Trader-Trapper; Journal of the Acoustical Society; Journal of Experimental Zoology; Journal of Mammalogy; Alfred A. Knopf; Little, Brown and Co.; Hugh C. MacLean Publications; McGraw-Hill Book Co.; Natural History Press; Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews; W. W. Norton and Co.; Oxford University Press; Perspectives in Biology and Medicine; Physiological Reviews; Popular Science; Progress in Physiological Psychology; Quarterly Review of Biology; Reader's Digest; W. B. Saunders Co.; Schenkman Publishing Co.; Science; University of Chicago Press; John Wiley and Sons; Yale University Press
  - Publishers - Reviews by Griffin (Box 10, Folder 103)
    Academic Press; American Weekly; The Auk; Behavioural Processes; Bird-Banding; Cambridge University Press; Dodd-Mead and Co.; E. P. Dutton; Ecology; Holiday House; Journal of the Acoustical Society of America; Journal of Comparative Physiology A; Journal of Experimental Zoology; Journal of Mammalogy; Journal of Theoretical Biology; Journal of Wildlife Management; Natur Wissenschaften; National Geographic; Nature; New York Academy of Sciences; Oxford Companion to Animal Behavior; Plenum; Psychological Bulletin; Princeton University Press; Royal Ontario Museum; W. B. Saunders Co.; Science; Scientific American; Smithsonian; Stanford University Press; John Wiley and Sons; Wilson Bulletin
  - Publishers - Scientific American (Box 10, Folder 104)
    bird migration; Creole Petroleum; oil birds; Venezuela; Discovery; Vision
  - Publishers - Time-Life (Box 10, Folder 105)
    Nina Leen; Animal Behavior; Beebe Tropical Research Station; Trinidad; Harvard University; New York Zoological Society; William H. Stiles; Cornell University
  - Pye, J. David (Box 10, Folder 106)
    Institute of Laryngology; England; bat recordings; Trinidad; University of London; Kings College; ultrasonic; Queen Mary College; Scientific American; C. L. Stong; Air Force Office of Scientific Research
  - Ra-Ri (Box 11, Folder 107)
    Rabin, Aaron - Rockefeller University; chemical senses. Rabor, D. S. - Silliman University; Philippines; caves in Mindanao. Racing Pigeon - publisher; supplier. Rainey, Dr. - Centre for Overseas Pest Research; London; Alison Steedman; bird migration. Ralls, Katherine - Kenya; New York Zoological Society; Uganda; Tanzania; Museum of Natural History; Smithsonian Institution; Millbrook. Rand, Austin L. - National Museum of Canada; bats. Randolph, Howard S. F. - bats in hair. Ransome, Roger D. - England; Bristol University; bat biology. Rao, K. Pampapathi - Andhra University; India; mussels;. Raper, John - Harvard University; women biologists; Christiana Leonard; Rockefeller University women status. Raspet, August - Mississippi State College; sailplane for research; bird migration. Raup, Hugh M. - Harvard University; forests;. Rayment, Robert - Meteorological Research, Royal Air Force; England. Raytheon Co. - Satellite Wildlife Research Program; biotelemetry study; radio tracking; Lester Garvin; W. Cochran; R. Suthers. RCA Laboratories - P. N. Yocom; transducer improvements; radar equipment. Rea, E. M. - bats in auditorium, New Orleans; Mardi Gras floats. Reed, Sheldon - University of Minnesota recruiting. Reille, Antoine - Laboratoire de Neurophysiologie, Paris; bird navigation. Reisman, Ron - University of Pennsylvania; psycholinguistics. Renn, Charles Easterday - Elisabeth Sheffield. Renshaw, Birdsey - University of Oregon Medical School. Research Center for Language and Semiotic Studies - Indiana University; Thomas Sebeok. Reuland, J. E. - R. M. Fasanella; Yale University School of Medicine; bird navigation. Rice, Charles E. - Stanford Research Institute; Kenyon College; echolocation. Rice, William R. - University of California, Davis; acoustical location of prey;. Richard, P. B. - beavers; publishing in English; Paris. Richardson, W. John - Cornell University; weather and bird flight; Millbrook. Richey, M. W. - Royal Geographical Society; England. Riggs, Austen - bird homing; effects of lights and aircraft on birds; University of Texas. Riggeih, Austen Fox - Cambridge, Massachusetts; bird homing. Ripley's Believe It or Not - erroneous publication. Ripley, S. Dillon - Peabody Museum of Natural History; Smithsonian Institution; Beebe Tropical Research Station. Ripon College - Wisconsin; commencement speech. Riss, Walter - Down State Medical Center; NY.
  - Ro-Ry (Box 11, Folder 108)
    Roberts, Brian - Scott Polar Research Institute; England; Antarctic birds. Robinson, Robert A. - Johns Hopkins Hospital; bat bones. Rockefeller Foundation - Dr. Pratt; Bellagio. Rocky Mountain Biological Lab - 1980 forms (blank). Rodriguez-Teijeiro, Jose D. - bird echolocation; Universidad de Barcelona. Roeder, Kenneth D. - Tufts University; film; moth ultrasonic receptors. Roer, Hubert - Zoologisches Forschungsinstitut; Germany; bat banding. Roffey, Jeremy - Centre for Overseas Pest Research; England; bird migration; insect radar. Rogers, Mary Ann - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute; Cornell University. Romeyn, J. A. - University of Alberta; Canada. Rose, Jerzy E. - John Hopkins University School of Medicine; live bats for neuro-anatomical study. Rose, William B. - Harvey Society lecture. Rosenblatt, Jay S. - Rutgers University; U.S. Ethological Conference Committee; Dr. Marie Luise Leder; City College. Rosenblum, Ann M. (Mrs. Murray) - bats in Mahopec, NY house. Rosenthal, Gerson M., Jr. - University of Chicago; birds and wind, climate effect. Ross, A. - Arizona Western College; bat food habit studies. Rostron, B. T. - bat vocal organs. Rouk, C. Stanley - Baylor University; bat stomach contents. Round, H. J. - bat sounds, microphones; England. Rowan, William - University of Alberta; Canada; bird migration and daylight; Lowell Institute; Biological Reviews. Rutschmann, J. - high frequency sound; NY State Psychiatric Institute. Rysgaard, George N. - University of Minnesota; Kellogg Bird Sanctuary; bird banding.
  - Rawson, Kenneth (Box 11, Folder 109)
    Max Planck Institute; bird orientation and time sense; University of Wisconsin; Arctic Aeromedical Laboratory; Swarthmore College; George Scott; Oberlin College; National Science Foundation; Gustav Kramer
  - Redfield, Alfred (Box 11, Folder 110)
    see Griffin, Donald R.-Family for personal correspondence; von Frisch; Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution; K. S. Lashley; Pete Scholander; van Dam; Arctic Aeromedical Laboratory; Air Force
  - Robinson, Doug and Sarah (Box 11, Folder 111)
    Cornell University; flight acoustic data; Skillman State Village; New Jersey
  - Robinson, Peggy (Box 11, Folder 112)
    Restricted from scholarly access.
  - Rockefeller University - Laboratory of Animal Behavior (Box 11, Folder 113)
    Armin Braun; Bucknell University; computer development; Dukane Corp.; Duke University; Dody Dunning; Eisenberg; Owen Floody; General Radio Co.; Grass Instrument Co.; Holgate detector; Jalbert Aerology Laboratory; Knowles Electronics; Bob Leader; Christiana M. Leonard; McGeorge, Lee; Millbrook, NY; Nantucket Kiteman; NBC television program on aggression; Carl Pfaffmann; David Pye; Randolph Air Force Base; Robert Schoenfeld; Frank Stubbs; Westinghouse Electric Corp.; Timothy Williams
  - Sa-Sd (Box 11, Folder 114)
    Sachs, Murray B. - Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine; pigeon nerve system. Saint Cyr, Edith - Nevada; teacher; bats and apples. Salmon, Michael - University of Illinois; bat film. Sanborn, Colin Campbell - Field Museum of Natural History; bat skins; lecture. Sanderson, Glen C. - Illinois Natural History Survey; Frank Bellrose; University of Illinois. Sandusky, O. E. - bat memo. Sanford, Thomas B. - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution; birds and electro-magnetic fields. Santa Cruz, Pat - bats in attic. Sarles, Harvey B. - University of Minnesota; Harry F. Guggenheim Foundation. Saunders, Frederick A. - Mt. Holyoke College; bird banding. Scarlett, William and Leah - Bonaventure Island; photographs of gannets. Schaps, Gary L. - bird migratory behavior; Washington University; Suga. Schilling, Harold K. - Pennsylvania State College; bat ultrasonic waves; high frequency sounds; equipment; larynx. Schleidt, Wolfgang - Max Planck Institute; Rawson; equipment. Schneider, Hans - Zoologisches Institut; Germany; bats catching insects; bat film. Schneirla, Ted C. - American Museum of Natural History; von Frisch film; Wilner Films and Slides; Alden Potter; E. J. Mauthner. Scholander, Per Frederick "Pete" and Susan - Swarthmore College; Alpha Helix; Point Barrow, Alaska; Woods Hole; U.S. Air Force; fur insulation properties; Knut Schmidt-Nielsen; diving animals. Schuck, O. H. - Minneapolis-Honeywell Regulator Co.; acoustic orientation. Schuz, Ernst - Kaiser Wilhelm Gesellschaft; Germany; bird navigation. Schwab, John L. - U.S. Chemical Corps; Camp Detrick, MD; Biological Dept.. Schwartzkopff, J. - Universitat Gottingen; Germany; bird wing sensitivity; Ruhr-Universitat Bochum. Schweitzer, Jeff (and father John) - Paleontology; American Museum of Natural History. Scichtman, M. - Bayside High School (NY); bat food. Scott, George T. - Bermuda Biological Station; NY; U.S. Army Air Force. Scott, John Paul - Roscoe Jackson Memorial Laboratory; Committee for Study of Animal Societies; bird navigation; von Frisch. Scott, Oliver - traps; mice; Barnstable. Scott, Peter - Wildfowl Trust, England; Jeremy Hatch; birds and thermal currents. Scribner, Kimball J. - Explorers Research Corp.; bird orientation; aviation research.
  - Se-Sm (Box 11, Folder 115)
    Seaman, Arlene R. - NY State University; bat and bird retina; Michigan State University; Beebe Tropical Research Station; Trinidad; New York Zoological Society. Sears, W. R. - bumblebee flight; Northrup Aircraft; Journal of Aeronautical Sciences. Sebeok, Thomas A. - East-West Center; animal communication book; Research Center for Language Sciences. Segedin, George J. - reference; Kaiser Engineers. Selander, Robert K. - spectrographs of cave swallows; University of Texas, Austin. Semple, John B. - Geographic article re bats. Sessions, Jack - poetry. Setlow, R. B. - DNA and life span; Oak Ridge National Laboratory. Seyfarth, Robert and Dorothy Cheney - monkeys in Africa; UCLA; University of Pennsylvania; see also Richard Garwin. Seymour, Christopher J. - bats as pets. Shaffer, Chester M. - bats in West Virginia. Shalter, Michael - Ruhr Universitat Bochum; bird echolocation; Germany. Shapovalov, Leo - California Division of Fish and Game; fish homing; Natural History Museum. Shaw, Henry S. - bird homing; Huyck Preserve; General Radio Co.; Kent Island. Shaw, Neil A. - Argonne National Laboratory; Woods Hole; bird radar; University of Melbourne; PLESSEY; acoustic sounders. Shea, John Bernard - National Geographic article re bats. Sheahan, Terence G. - National Geographic article re bats. Sheldon, Walter H. - Emory University School of Medicine; bats for experiments. Shelley, Lewis O. - bat colonies. Sherman, Frederick G. - Brown University; Kennedy; Goldsmith; Novick. Sherman, H. B. - University of Florida; bat food; cages; NIH grant; bat banding. Shilling, C. W. - George Washington University; bat sonar; see also U.S. Office of Naval Research. Shull, A. Franklin - University of Michigan; flying bat photo. Shy, Eyal - Hebrew University of Jerusalem; graduate student application. Sibley, Charles C. - Cornell University; ornithology. Sikkel, P. P. H. - bat eradication; architects; South Africa. Sikorsky, Igor - Vought-Sikorsky Aircraft Corp.; helicopters to observe birds. Silva, Gilberto - bats in Cuba; Instituto Nacional de Reforma Agraria. Simon, James R. - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park; pelican research. Simpson, Myron L. - Johns Hopkins University; bats for experiments. Skinner, B. F. - pigeon visual recognition; bird radar; Indiana University; psychology; war work. Skinner, Dorothy M. - Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Woods Hole; bird navigation;. Skoryna, Stanley - McGill University; bat echolocation. Slocum, Lloyd V. - Woods Hole; Charles and Libby Marsh; Pennsylvania State University; electrical engineer. Small, S. N. - bats. Smith, Alpheus W. - Ohio State University; bat supersonic sounds; photograph for physics textbook. Smith, James Dale - University of Kansas; bat acoustics; California State University; Trinidad; Venezuela; Holgate detector. Smith, Jane C. - Queen Mary College; London; use of image in article. Smith, Jeri D. - bat spiraling. Smith, G. Maskill - New Zealand Scientific Liaison Office; birds and supersonic sound. Smith, Ralph and Todd (wife) - Aviation Medicine; U.S. Air Force; University of California-Berkeley; Payne Pearson; University of Glasgow; Scotland; Aviation Medicine, Randolph Field, Texas;. Smithsonian Institution - National Zoological Park; Ernest P. Walker; bat supply; films; A. Wetmore. Smullin, David - Alaska; job assistance. Smyth, Dermot M. - James Cook University of North Queensland; Long Pocket Laboratories; Australia.
  - Sn-Sz (Box 12, Folder 116)
    Snake King - supplier of birds and animals; Texas. Snow, Edward R. - Sable Island fauna; Massachusetts. Snow, Thomas J. - translator of Russian publications. Snyder, Russell L. - Physical Oceanographic Laboratory, Nova University; bird navigation; whitecap sounds; Torre-Bueno. Solomon, Richard L. - Harvard University Laboratory of Social Relations. Spaet, Bernate - Cornell University student; Columbia University. Spear, Philip J. - National Pest Control Association; rats and ultrasonic noise. Speidel, Carl C. - University of Virginia; films. Sperry Gyroscope Company - bird navigation; navigating instruments. Speirs, J. Murray - bird navigation; meteorology; Ontario, Canada. Stabler, Robert M. - University of Pennsylvania; owls; Philadelphia Zoological Garden. Stack, C. R. - bird hearing; infrared light; Instituto Neurologico de Colombia; Jaime Gomez. Steel, Liza - bird equilibrium. Stein, David - bat detectors; Argentina; New York Zoological Society. Stetson, Harlan T. - homing pigeons and radio waves; U.S. Signal Corps. Stewart, James L. - Naval Electronics Laboratory; bats and echoes. Stewart, K. R. - high frequency sound waves. Stewart, Rodney Mason - poem. Stewart, Walter - Rockefeller University; National Institutes of Health; wildfire toxin. Stiles, Mabel - banded bird. Stokes, Allen W. - Trinidad; Tobago; birds. Stone, G. C. "Didi" - Harvard University; film. Stone, Jeannette Galambos - Vassar College; Sarah Lawrence College. Stone, L. S. - Yale University; film. Stong, C. L. - ultrasonic sounds of bats; Scientific American; David Pye; circuit amplifier. Storrs, Eleanor E. - Gulf South Research Institute; armadillos. Straw, Richard M. - insect versus human eyes; Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden. Streicher, Eugene - University of Chicago; bird navigation; see also U.S. Army Chemical Center. Strelkov, P. O. - Academy of Sciences; Leningrad, Russia. Stresemann, Erwin - Zoologisches Museum; Germany; bird orientation. Strohl, I. - bats; Switzerland; Zoological Institute. Strong, Susie - friend. Strupp, Barbara - Cornell University. Stuart, Alastair M. - National Institutes of Health; Australia;. Suga, Nobuo - Washington University; DRG research associate; Rockefeller University. Summers, D. M. - University of Victoria; bird eyes. Supa, Michael - International Business Machines; experiments with blind. Svendsen, Gerald E. - Ohio University; pika and hay. Swan, Lawrence W. - San Francisco State College; radar bird watching in India. Swarthmore College - Honors examiner; L. R. Shero.
  - Schaefer, Glen W. (Box 12, Folder 117)
    England; University of Technology; bird migration; New Brunswick, Canada; radar; Woods Hole
  - Schmidt-Koenig, Klaus (Box 12, Folder 118)
    Universitat Tubingen; bird navigation
  - Schmidt-Nielsen, Knut (Box 12, Folder 119)
    University of Cincinnati; sensory physiology; Duke University; Pete Scholander
  - Schnitzler, Hans- Ulrich (Box 12, Folder 120)
    Zoophysiologisches Institut; Tubingen; Germany; Alvin Novick; Yale University; Rockefeller University; National Science Foundation; bat echolocation; James Simmon; New York Zoological Society; Trinidad; J. W. Goethe Universitat
  - Simmons, James (Box 12, Folder 121)
    Acoustical Society of America; bat echoes; Beebe Tropical Research Station; Brown University; Ed Buchler; Colombia; Fachbereich Biologie; Brock Fenton; Germany; Jamaica; Tony Lavender; Beatrice Lawrence; Millbrook, NY; J. Molinari; National Science Foundation; New Guinea; Panama; Princeton University; sound recording equipment; Nobua Suga; Susi Torre-Bueno; Trinidad; U. S. Department of Health and Human Services; University of California, Berkeley; University of Oregon; Washington University; Woods Hole
  - Singer, Marcus (Box 12, Folder 122)
    House Un-American Activities Affairs Committee; communism; Cornell University; Harvard University; Howard Adelmann; George Adams; Paul O'Leary
  - Sokolov, Vladimir (Box 12, Folder 123)
    Harvard College; International Student Service; Alden H. Miller; Moscow University; Rockefeller University; J. Schwartzkopff; University of California-Berkeley; USSR Academy of Sciences; see also Konstantinov
  - Steen, Johan B. (Box 12, Folder 124)
    pigeon homing; University of Tromso; Norway; Rockefeller Foundation; University of Oslo; Harold T.'Ted' Hammel; Pete F. Scholander; Harvard University; Office of Naval Research
  - Suthers, Roderick A. (Box 12, Folder 125)